

Moegammad Siraaj Jeftha

Aspiring Software Engineer

Recent Software Engineering Bootcamp Graduate at HyperionDev with 2 years of working experience in the Telecommunication Industry. Highly skilled in sales and marketing, java, python, SQL and machine learning. Ambitious and forward thinking Digital Transformation enthusiast who enjoys a challenge. Currently seeking an opportunity to use experience and new skill set in a positive way.

Email:

sirjeftha@gmail.com

Mobile:

0715282503

Location:

Cape Town

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/in/Siraaj-Jeftha

Github:

https://github.com/Siraaj26

Professional Goals

I seeks to one dat lead an engineer team, leveraging my technical and customer relations expertise to deliver best-in-class solutions in B2B and B2C.

Skills

- Java
- Python
- Proactive Problem Solver
- Decisive
- Teamwork
- Public Speaking
- Communication
- Attention to Detail
- Critical Thinking
- Analytical Thinking
- Creative Thinking
- Time Management
- Data Visualization and Presentation
- Research and Strategy
- Adaptable
- Goal Orientated

Education

HyperionDev | February 2021 - July 2021

Certificate of Completion | Software Engineering

- Programming
- Software Engineering
- Data Science and Advanced Algorithms

North West University | March 2020 - September 2020

Certificate of Completion | Technology Management for Non-Technical Management NQF Level 4

- Telecommunication Strategy Management
- Marketing analysis and marketing strategy
- 50

North West University | March 2019 - January 2020

Certificate of Completion | Programme in Enterprise and Technology Management NQF level 4

- Digital Transformation
- Project Management
- Agile Methodologies and agile management
- Information Communication Technology
- Internet of things (IoT)

University of the Western Cape | February 2018 - November 2018

Honours in Information Systems

- Strategic Management and Project Management
- Business analysis and delivering IS benefits
- Procurement and Logistics
- Knowledge Management (Research)
- Digital Privacy and Security

Education (Self Study)

Udemy Courses

- C++ PROGRAMMING by DIGIFLAX E-LEARNING
- Complete Python Bootcamp by Jose Portilla, Head of Data Science, Pierian Data Inc.
- 100 Days of Code The Complete Python Pro Bootcamp for 2021 by Dr Angela Yu.
- Python for Data Science and Machine Learning by Jose Portilla, Head of Data Science, Pierian Data Inc.
- The Ultimate MySQL Bootcamp by Colt Steele and Ian Schoonover.

Systems

Oracle DBMS

- Retrieved and utilize data
- Create Information for presenting performance.

Qlick Sense

 Utilizing data for performance reporting and high level presentations.

Languages

English Afrikaans

Interest

- Artificial Intelligence
- Cyber Security
- Internet of things (IoT)
- Machine Learning
- Cloud Computing
- Cooking
- Reading
- Chess

Achievements

Implemented a new Business Improvement Model at Vodacom

November 2019 - January 2021

- Initiating a new proof of concept (POC) improving customer care and service.
- The model incorporated new processes and the redesigning of current processes.
- The model improved service delivery times and customer satisfaction.

Founded UWC FUTURE Tech Club February 2019 - July 2019

- Creation of a new student initiative to

- mentor high school students to understand
 Information Communication Technology.
- Create partnership with technology organizations to teach new technological trends and the role of future generations in the new technological age.
- Develop relationship with high schools to implement technology sessions.

Joined Golden Key International Honours Society

November 2017 - Present

- Achieved Academic Goals and became a Golden Key Member.

Work Experience

Internship - Consumer Business Unit (CBU)

Vodacom | February 2019 - January 2021

- Responsible for end to end service delivery management, improving processes and improving the experience of customers.
- Optimized data collection using Oracle DBMS, significantly enhancing all stakeholders ability to find required information quickly and effectively.
- Initiated and managed new reports with excel to improve strategies and operations.
- Conducted market analysis, presenting finding and recommendations to senior management team using Powerpoint, Power BI and google documents.
- Initiated the development of new solutions and a new improvement model.
- Increased revenue growth by 86% in 2019 and 79% in 2020.

Sales Consultant

Cell Express | March 2017 - December 2018

- Analyzed specific needs of customers, increasing profits through the procurement of in demand products and services.
- Implemented a new stock process ensuring that in demand products are always on hand while freeing up additional capital and storage space.
- Fostered strong relationships with customers and strategic associates, while improving customer experience by addressing issues and concerns.

Tutor (Marketing and Operations) and Student Assistant University of the Western Cape | February 2017 - October 2018

- Tutored 175 students in Marketing and Operations, with a subsequent pass rate of 100%.
- Provided students with weekly progress reports, setting learning objectives and tracking their improvement.
- Assisted Lecturers with content assimilation and development of tutorials, tests and assignments.
- Composed my own class room material, focused at developing students communication skills and applying the knowledge learned.

Volunteer Experience

Club Leader

UWC FUTURE TECH CLUB | February 2019 - November 2019

- UWC student initiative aimed at improving digital inclusion in South Africa.
- Visited underprivileged high school to equip both students and teachers with the knowledge and e-skills such as VR/AR, Socrative, Coding, Digital Literacy and Digital citizenship.

Student Mentor

University of the Western Cape | August 2018 - August 2019

- Student Mentor as part of UWC Women's Month Project in creating ICT awareness and career prospects in the field of technology.
- Multiple schools participated in events in coding, digital literacy, motivational speakers and information session of future careers in technology.

References

Penny Jenkins - Portfolio Manager Contact Details: On request Philip Robinson - HR Manager Contact Details: On request

Dean Africa - Service Manager Contact Details: On request Gasodien Jaffer - Store Owner Contact Details: On request